Consider this image of a dog.
看看这张小狗图像
A single region in this image may have many different patterns that we want to detect.
图像中的单个区域可能有很多需要我们检测的规律
Consider this region for instance.
例如这个区域
This region has teeth,
这个区域有牙齿
some whiskers, and a tongue.
几根胡须和舌头
In that case, to understand this image,
这样的话 要理解这幅图像
we need filters for detecting all three of these characteristics,
我们就需要用于检测所有这三种特性的过滤器
one for each teeth, whiskers, and tongue.
牙齿 胡须和舌头分别对应一个过滤器
Recall the case of a single convolutional filter.
还记得之前的单个卷积过滤器吗？
Adding another filter is probably exactly what you'd expect,
添加另一个过滤器几乎完全一样
where we just populate an additional collection of nodes in the convolutional layer.
我们只需在卷积层中填充另一组节点
This collection has its own shared set of
这个集合具有自己的共享权重集
weights that differ from the weights for the blue nodes above them.
与上方蓝色节点的权重不同
In fact, it's common to have
实际上 在一个卷积层中拥有数十个或数百个
tens to hundreds of these collections in a convolutional layer,
这种节点集合是很常见的
each corresponding to their own filter.
每个都对应自己的过滤器
Let's now execute some code to see what these collections look like.
我们现在运行一些代码 看看这些集合的代码如何
After all, each is formatted in the same way as an image,
毕竟 每个的形成方式都和图像的一样
namely as a matrix of values.
即值矩阵
We'll be visualizing the output of a Jupyter Notebook.
我们将可视化 Jupyter Notebook 的输出
If you like, you can follow along with the link below.
如果你愿意的话 可以点击下面的链接跟着操作
So, say we're working with an image of Udacity's self-driving car as input.
假设我们要处理的输入图像是优达学城的无人驾驶汽车
Let's use four filters,
我们使用四个过滤器
each four pixels high and four pixels wide.
每个都高 4 个像素 宽 4 个像素
Recall, each filter will be convolved across the height and width of
每个过滤器将在图像的宽和高上卷积
the image to produce an entire collection of nodes in the convolutional layer.
以在卷积层中形成整个节点集合
In this case, since we have four filters,
这里 因为我们有四个过滤器
we'll have four collections of nodes.
因此将有四组节点
In practice we will refer to each of
在实际操作中
these four collections as either feature maps or as activation maps.
我们将这四个集合称为特征图或激活图
When we visualize these feature maps,
当我们可视化这些特征图时
we see that they look like filtered images.
我们看到它们看起来像过滤后的图像
That is, we've taken all of the complicated,
即我们从原始图像中拿走
dense information in the original image,
所有复杂的密集信息
and in each of these four cases,
并在每个集合中
outputted a much simpler image with less information.
输出信息更少的更简单图像
By peeking at the structure of the filters,
通过观察这些过滤器的结构
you can see that the first two filters discover vertical edges,
可以发现前两个过滤器发现了垂直边缘
where the last two detect horizontal edges in the image.
后两个过滤器检测到图像中的水平边缘
Remember that lighter values in the feature map
特征图中浅色的值
mean that the pattern in the filter was detected in the image.
表示在图像中发现了过滤器中的规律
So, can you match the lighter regions in
你能将每个特征图中的浅色区域
each feature map with their corresponding areas in the original image?
与原始图像的相应区域进行匹配吗？
In this activation map, for instance,
例如在这个激活图中
we can see a clear white line defining the right edge of the car.
我们可以看到一条清晰的白色线条 表示汽车的右侧边缘
This is because all of the corresponding regions in the car image closely resemble
这是因为汽车图像中的所有对应区域与过滤器很相似
the filter where we have a vertical line of
垂直浅色像素的左侧是
dark pixels to the left of a vertical line of lighter pixels.
垂直深色像素线条
If you think about it you'll notice that edges and images appear as
如果思考下 会发现图像中的边缘
a line of lighter pixels next to a line of darker pixels.
显示为在深色像素旁边的浅色像素线条
This image for instance contains many regions that would be
例如这个图像包含很多可以被之前定义的
discovered or detected by one of the four filters we defined before.
四个过滤器之一发现或检测到的区域
Filters that function as edge detectors are very important in CNNs,
在 CNN 中充当边缘检测器的函数非常重要
and we'll revisit them later.
稍后我们会继续讲解
So, now we know how to understand
现在我们知道什么是
convolutional layers that have a grayscale image as input.
将灰度图像作为输入的卷积层了
But, what about color images?
那么彩色图像呢？
Well, we've seen that grayscale images are interpreted by the computer as a 2D array.
我们知道灰度图像被计算机解读为
Width, height, and width.
具有宽和高的二维数组
Color images are interpreted by the computer as a 3D array.
彩色图像则被计算机解读为
With, height width, and depth.
具有宽度 高度和深度的三维数组
In the case of RGB images the depth is three.
对于 RGB 图像 深度是 3
This 3D array is best conceptualized as a stack of three two-dimensional matrices.
这些三维矩阵可以理解为三个二维矩阵堆叠到了一起
Where we have matrices corresponding to the red,
这些矩阵对应的是图像的红色
green, and blue channels of the image.
绿色和蓝色通道
So, how do we perform a convolution on a color image.
那么如何对彩色图像进行卷积处理呢？
As well as the case with grayscale images,
和灰度图像一样
we still move a filter horizontally and vertically across the image.
依然在图像上水平及垂直地移动过滤器
Only now the filter is itself three-dimensional to have a value for
但是现在过滤器本身是三维的
each color channel at each horizontal and vertical location in the image array.
对于图像数组中每个水平和垂直位置的颜色通道都有一个值
Just as we think of the color image as a stack of three two-dimensional matrices,
就像我们将彩色图像看做三个二维矩阵的堆叠一样
you can also think of the filter as a stack of three, two-dimensional matrices.
也可以将过滤器看做三个二维矩阵的堆叠
Both the color image and the filter have red,
彩色图像和过滤器都拥有红色
green, and blue channels.
绿色和蓝色通道
Now to obtain the values of the nodes in the feature map corresponding to this filter,
要从特征图中获取对应于该过滤器的节点值
we do pretty much the same thing we did before.
流程和之前的差不多
Only now are some as over three times as many terms.
只是现在求和的项是之前的三倍
We emphasize that here we've depicted the calculation
这里计算的是彩色图像上
of the value of a single node in a convolutional layer,
一个过滤器的
for one filter on a color image.
卷积层中一个节点的值
If we wanted to picture the case of a color image with
如果要表示具有多个过滤器的彩色图像
multiple filters instead of having a single 3D array which corresponds to one filter,
而不是对应一个过滤器的一个三维数组
we would define multiple 3D arrays each defining a filter.
我们需要定义多个三维数组 每个定义一个过滤器
Here we've depicted three filters.
这里我们描绘了三个过滤器
Each is a 3D array that you can think of as a stack of three, 2D arrays.
每个都是一个三维数组 可以看做三个二维数组的堆叠
Here's where it starts to get really cool.
现在到了精彩的部分了
You can think about each of the feature maps in a convolutional layer along
你可以将沿着相同线条的卷积层中的每个特征图
the same lines as an image channel and stuck them to get a 3D array.
看做一个图像通道 将它们堆叠就能获得三维数组
Then, we can use this 3D array as input to
然后可以将此三维数组
still another convolutional layer to discover
当做依然是另一个卷积层的输入
patterns within the patterns that we discovered in the first convolutional layer.
以便从我们在第一个卷积层中发现的规律中发现规律
We can then do this again to discover patterns within patterns within patterns.
然后可以继续这么做 从规律中发现规律 然后继续从规律中发现规律
Remember that in some sense convolutional layers
注意 从某种程度上来说
aren't too different from the dense layers that you saw in the previous section.
卷积层和你在上一部分见到的密集层区别不大
Dense layers are fully connected.
密集层是完全连接的
Meaning that the nodes are connected to every node in the previous layer.
意味着节点与前一层级中的每个节点相连
Convolutional layers are locally connected.
卷积层是局部相连的
Where their nodes are connected to only a small subset of the previously S nodes.
节点仅与上一层级中的一小部分节点相连
Convolutional layers also had this added parameter sharing,
卷积层还具有参数共享特性
but in both cases with convolutional and dense layers,
但是对于卷积层和密集层来说
inference works the same way.
推理的工作原理是一样的
Both have weights and biases that are initially randomly generated.
二者的权重和偏差一开始都是随机生成的
So, in the case of CNNs where the weights take the form of convolutional filters,
对于 CNN 来说 权重是卷积过滤器形式
those filters are randomly generated,
这些过滤器是随机生成的
and so are the patterns that they're initially designed to detect.
一开始检测的规律也是随机的
As with ML piece when we construct a CNN we will always specify a loss function.
和 NLP 一样 当我们构建 CNN 时 始终会指定损失函数
In the case of multiclass classification this will be categorical cross entropy loss.
对于多类别分类 将是分类交叉熵损失
Then as we train the model through back propagation,
然后通过反向传播训练模型
the filters are updated at each epic to take on values that minimize the loss function.
在每个周期都会更新过滤器 以便设定可以最小化损失函数的值
In other words, the CNN determines what kind of
换句话说 CNN 根据损失函数
patterns it needs to detect based on the loss function.
确定它需要检测什么样的规律
We'll visualize these patterns later and see that for instance,
稍后我们将可视化这些规律
if our data set contains dogs,
例如查看我们的数据集是否包含狗狗
the CNN is able to on its own learn filters that look like dogs.
CNN 能够自己学习看起来像狗狗的过滤器
So, with CNN's to emphasize we won't specify
强调下 对于 CNN 我们不会指定过滤器值
the values of the filters or tell the CNN what kind of patterns it needs to detect.
或者告诉 CNN 它需要检测什么样的规律
These will be learned from the data.
而是从数据中学习